# Jack Kieny

SQL Developer at National Indemnity Company

(402) 850-0748 | jackkieny@cox.net





(C) jackkieny (m) li-jackkieny

# **SUMMARY**

SQL Developer with 2+ years of experience in database and ETL process management. I possess strong technical skills in software development, database management, algorithms, and data structures. I have experience working with multiple different programming languages and frameworks. I also have experience developing RESTful APIs, containerizing and deploying applications. I am detail-oriented, proactive, eager to learn and further develop my skills as a software engineer.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### NATIONAL INDEMNITY COMPANY | SOL DEVELOPER

June 2023 - Present | Omaha, NE

- → Manage and maintain 15+ applications deployed enterprise-wide
- → Develop and optimize SQL queries and stored procedures
- → Support ETL processes across data warehouse applications
- → Collaborate within an Agile Scrum team to deliver solutions in a timely manner

## CHICK-FIL-A | MANAGER

June 2020 - March 2023 | Lincoln, NE

- → Commitment to quest satisfaction, quality standards and a sense of urgency
- → Managed a team of individuals to ensure that labor and productivity goals were met
- → Cash management, daily team huddles, problem solving skills, adaptive and independent

# **PROJECTS**

RECODING PLUM | SQL DEVELOPER | C# • VB.NET • SQL

November 2023 - June 2024 | Null Penguins - Data Warehouse

- → Primary developer to optimize flat file output for ETL processes
- → Reduced the run-time of upload application and manual verification workload for premium processors by simplifying coverage fields from vehicle-level to policy-level
- → Tailored recoding processes to meet specific coverage requirements across 42 states

#### A NEW PYP3DB | PRODUCT MANAGER/BACKEND DEVELOPER |

August 2021 - May 2022 | Senior Design - University Sponsored Project

- → Served as product manager on senior design team building a full stack web application
- → Implemented standard software engineering practices (e.g. Agile, Testing, Daily Standup)
- → Led weekly team meetings to track requirements, design, and functionality
- → Proficient in Python, Flask, and Django

## SKILLS

#### **PROGRAMMING**

Languages:

Python • C • C#

Go • JavaScript

Databases:

SQL • MongoDB

Frameworks

React • Flask • Django

Tools Platforms:

Git • Docker • Kubernetes

# **EDUCATION**

# UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA-LINCOLN

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE MINOR IN MATHEMATICS December 2022 | Lincoln, NE School of Engineering

## REFERENCES

Mike Stice Owner/Operator CHICK-FIL-A 48TH AND O STREET

mike.stice@cfafranchisee.com

W: +1 (402) 465-0075

M: +1 (785) 614-5162

**Darian Gemmell** Instructor

**ECHO COLLECTIVE** 

FORMER SUPERVISOR

□ darian.beard@hotmail.com

M: +1 (402) 202-5928

**Bob Copple** President

ASCENSION VIA CHRISTI HOSPITAL FORMER SCOUTMASTER

□ robert.copple@viachristi.org

M: +1 (402) 616-1661